smartnews.com 2015-04-07

# SmartNews Privacy Policy

## Last Updated: October 1, 2014

Protecting your privacy is really important to us. Accordingly, we’re providing this Privacy Policy to explain our practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information that we receive when you use our Services. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any third-party websites, services or applications, even if they are accessible through our Services. Any information that we collect is subject to the privacy policy in effect at the time that Information is collected. We may, however, modify and revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we’ll notify you of those changes by posting them on the Services or other notification, and we’ll indicate when those changes will become effective. Also, please note that, unless we define a term in this Privacy Policy, all capitalized words used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of Service.

## How do we collect and use information?

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Services, to administer your use of the Services, and to enable you to enjoy and easily navigate our Services.

**Information Provided by You or Collected with Your Permission.** If you want to use certain features of the Services, we’ll collect certain information that can be used to identify you ( **“PII”** ) and/or other non-identifying information, including your use of certain social networking services ( **“SNS”** ) and information available on your SNS accounts. For example, if you let us know that you want to see what news stories the people you follow on Twitter are sharing, the links to these news stories will be sent to you via our Services. Please refer to the privacy policy for the SNS you use for more information on how your information will be shared by the SNS.

**Information Related to Your Use of the Services.** Our servers automatically record certain information about how you use our Services, such as the pages or features of our Services you browse and the time you spend on those pages or features, the links (including ads) on our Services that you click on, and other statistics. We use this information to administer the Services. We also analyze (and may engage third parties to analyze) this information to improve and enhance our Services by expanding their features and functionality and tailoring them to our users’ needs and preferences.

**Information Sent by Your Mobile Device.** We collect certain information that your mobile device sends when you use our Services, like user settings and the operating system. 

**Location Information.** We will collect information about your location and/or use various technologies to determine your location, such as sensor data from your device that provides information on nearby Wi-Fi access points and cell towers, if you enable this feature on the Services. You can enable or disable location services when you use our Services through your mobile device settings. We may use location information to improve and personalize our Services for you.

## What Information Do We Share With Third Parties?

We will not share any PII that we have collected from you except as described below:

**Information Shared with Our Services Providers.** We may engage third party service providers to work with us to administer and provide the Services. These third-party services providers have access to your PII only for the purpose of performing services on our behalf. For example, we use Google Analytics, in addition to our own analytics technology, and other third-party analytics packages to collect, monitor and analyze the information we collect in order to increase SmartNews’s functionality and user-friendliness, to better tailor the Services to our users’ needs, and to understand and analyze how you are using our Services. We also share your information with Google as necessary to receive the Google Analytics service. For more information please see Google’s privacy policy (<http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>) addressing the information that is collected to provide the Google Analytics service and how Google uses such information.

**Information Shared with Third Parties.** We may share aggregated information and non-identifying information with third parties for industry research and analysis, demographic profiling and other similar purposes.

**Information Disclosed in Connection with Business Transactions.** Information that we collect from our users, including PII, is considered to be a business asset. As a result, if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy or if we are acquired as a result of a transaction such as a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your PII may be disclosed or transferred to the third-party acquirer in connection with the transaction.

**Information Disclosed for Our Protection and the Protection of Others.** We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials or private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We may disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate: (i) to respond to claims, legal process (including subpoenas); (ii) to protect our property, rights and safety and the property, rights and safety of a third party or the public in general; and (iii) to stop any activity that we consider illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

**Information We Disclose With Your Consent or at Your Request.** We will share your PII with third-party sites or platforms, such as social networking sites, if you have expressly requested that we do so.

## The Security of Your Information

We take reasonable measures to protect the information that we collect from or about you (including your PII) from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Please be aware, however, that no method of transmitting information over the Internet or storing information is completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of any information.

## Links to Other Sites

Our Services may contain links to other websites and services. Any information that you provide on or to a third-party website or service is provided directly to the owner of the website or service and is subject to that party's privacy policy. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to such websites or services and we’re not responsible for the content, privacy or security practices and policies of those websites or services. To protect your information we recommend that you carefully review the privacy policies of other websites and services that you access.

## Modifying Your Information

If you want us to delete your PII, please contact us at privary@smartnews.com with your request. We’ll take steps to delete your information as soon as is practicable, but some information may remain in archived/backup copies for our records or as otherwise required by law.

## International Transfer

Your PII may be transferred to, and maintained on, computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you’re located outside the United States and choose to provide your PII to us, we may transfer your PII to the United States and process it there. 

## Our Policy Toward Children

Our Services are not directed to children under 13 and we do not knowingly collect PII from children under 13. If we learn that we have collected PII of a child under 13 we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible.

## Questions?

Please contact us at privacy@smartnews.com if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy.

スマートニュース株式会社（以下「当社」）は、高度情報通信社会における個人情報保護の重要性を認識し、当社が提供する各種サービス（以下「本サービス」）において、以下の通りプライバシーポリシー（以下「本ポリシー」）を定め、徹底をはかります。 

## 個人情報の定義

本ポリシーにおいて「個人情報」とは、生存する個人に関する情報であって、当該情報に含まれる氏名、生年月日その他の記述等により特定の個人を識別することができるもの（他の情報と容易に照合することができ、それにより特定の個人を識別することができることとなるものも含む）を指します。

## 個人情報の取得

当社は、適法かつ公正な手段によって個人情報を取得します。

## 個人情報の利用

当社は、個人情報を、以下に示す目的の範囲内で、業務の遂行上必要な限りにおいて利用します。

  * 本サービスのユーザ個人に対して最適化された情報を配信するため
  * 統計的分析により本サービスの品質向上に役立てるため
  * 本サービスに対するお問い合わせへの対応のため
  * 本サービスに関するアンケートを実施するため
  * 当社の実施するキャンペーンや新製品等に関するご案内をお送りするため
  * その他、上記の利用目的に付随する目的

## クッキーについて

当社は、本サービスサイトにおいて、クッキーを利用します。また、広告システムの一部においても、クッキーを利用することがあります。クッキーとは、ブラウザとサーバとの間で送受信した利用履歴等を、利用者の端末にファイルとして保存する技術です。利用者が、当社がクッキーを利用することを望まないときは、ご自分のブラウザにおいて、クッキーを拒否するよう設定することができます。ただし、クッキーを拒否した場合、ウェブサイトにおける本サービスの利用に際し、影響が生じる可能性があります。

## 行動ターゲティング広告の無効化について

本サービスは「行動ターゲティング広告」を提供しています。行動ターゲティング広告とは、利用者の行動履歴情報等を取得、利用し、利用者の興味・嗜好・属性を分析してインターネット広告を出し分けるサービスです。行動履歴情報等には、特定の個人を識別できる情報は含まれませんが、自社サービス内において取得する、もしくは、外部サービスより提供される性別・年齢・所在地等の情報を含むことがあります。もし、行動ターゲティング広告の配信をご希望されない場合は、[こちら](http://smartnews-ads.com/optout/)をクリックし、その手続きにしたがって無効化（以下、「オプトアウト」）をしてください。オプトアウトした後は、原則として、利用者への行動ターゲティング広告の配信はされなくなります。ただし、これらは行動履歴関連広告を停止するものであり、広告表示を完全に停止するものではありません。また、ブラウザの変更、クッキーの削除および新しい端末への変更、その他の事情により当社のオプトアウトがなされず、再度のオプトアウトが必要となることがありますのでご了承ください。

## 個人情報の第三者提供

当社は、法令に定める場合を除き、個人情報を事前に本人の同意を得ることなく第三者に提供しません。

なお、当社は、次の場合には、個人情報にアクセスし、これを第三者に開示することがあります。

  * 利用者本人の同意がある場合
  * 法令または裁判所、行政機関等の法令に基づく判決、決定、命令等により開示を求められた場合
  * 当社の権利または財産を保護および防御するための措置に合理的に必要な場合
  * 当社やお客様、またはその他一般の人々の生命、身体または財産を保護するために必要な場合であって、利用者の同意を得ることが困難であるとき
  * 公衆衛生の向上または児童の健全な育成の推進のために特に必要な場合であって、利用者の同意を得ることが困難であるとき
  * 国の機関もしくは地方公共団体またはその委託を受けた者が法令の定める事務を遂行することに対して協力する必要がある場合であって、利用者の同意を得ることにより当該事務の遂行に支障を及ぼすおそれがあるとき
  * 統計的データなど利用者本人を識別することができない状態で開示・提供する場合

## 個人情報の管理

  * 当社は、個人情報の正確性を保ち、これを安全に管理します。
  * 当社は、個人情報の紛失、破壊、改ざんまたは漏えい等を防止するため、適正な情報セキュリティ対策を講じます。
  * 当社は、運営体制の整備や社員の教育等を通じて、個人情報を適切に管理し、個人情報の紛失、破壊、改ざんまたは漏えい等に対する予防措置を講じます。 

## 個人情報の利用目的の通知、開示、訂正、利用停止等の求め

当社は、個人情報について、開示、訂正・追加・削除、利用停止・消去、第三者提供の停止または利用目的の通知にかかるお客様ご本人からの申出があった場合には、申出をいただいた方が本人であることを確認の上、個人情報保護法の定めにしたがい、誠実かつ速やかに対応します。 

なお、申出が個人情報保護法の定める要件をみたさない場合、または、個人情報保護法その他の法令により、開示等を拒絶することが認められる事由がある場合には、申出に沿えないことがあります。 

また、開示等の求めに対してお客様から当社に支払っていただく手数料等はありません。ただし、お客様から当社宛の通信費、交通費および上記に定める本人確認の際にお客様側で資料等の準備を行っていただく際に発生する費用等については、お客様の負担とさせていただきます。 

## プライバシーポリシーの改定

当社は、個人情報の取り扱いに関する運用状況を適宜見直し、継続的な改善に努めるものとし、必要に応じて、本ポリシーを変更することがあります。変更後のプライバシーポリシーは、本サイト上で随時公表するものとします。 

## お問い合わせ先

当社の個人情報の取り扱いに関するお問い合わせは、privacy@smartnews.com 宛にお願いいたします。

2012年12月1日制定  
2014年10月8日改定  
2015年2月13日改定  
スマートニュース株式会社（旧社名・株式会社ゴクロ）
